<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Thoughts and other words]]></title>
  <link href="http://intiocean.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://intiocean.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-20T22:01:17+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://intiocean.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Inti Ocean]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C is a very nice high level language]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/10/c-is-a-very-nice-high-level-language/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-10-20T21:19:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/10/c-is-a-very-nice-high-level-language</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quote which made me smile today.</p>

<blockquote><p>C is a very nice high level language with many of the modern programming constructs in it. The thing thats very important about it is that it lets you avoid the details of the machine when you want to, but when you need to, and sometimes when you&#8217;re writing an operating system you really do need to, you can get at the details of the machine and control everything. But you&#8217;re not forced to do that and thats important because that means you can write operating systems in this language and still have something that can be portable to other machines.</p><footer><strong>John R. Mashey 1982</strong> <cite><a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=tc4ROCJYbm0">The UNIX Operating System</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do what you enjoy]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/05/do-what-you-enjoy/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-05-11T18:31:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/05/do-what-you-enjoy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was having a coffee today at my local coffee shop and I had a moment of inspiration and scribbled over both sides of an index card. This is more or less what I wrote.</p>

<p>-</p>

<p>The necessity of having to take something from start to end is stopping me being as productive/creative/happy as I could be. In order to improve this I need to accept that it’s okay to pick some work up, take it forward a little and then let it lie or let someone else continue it. Because even though when considered from a top down view this doesn’t seem the most efficient way of doing things, it allows one to do what <em>really</em> interests us without constantly feeling guilty of all the things we have not completed. Instead of feeling guilty, we should feel proud of the work we have done even if we didn’t take the work over the finish line we have still helped it along the way.</p>

<p>What does it mean to have completed something [a piece of work] in this age of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_worker">knowledge workers</a>? There are more knowledge workers than ever before and this makes me think that we can’t hold on to the same definition of <em>complete</em> that we all currently have. I think we need a new notion of complete, a more agile notion and one which conveys that complete just means complete for me, complete for now. Not necessarily complete forever or for everyone.</p>

<p>When is a software package or library complete? At the first release, second, tenth? When it’s decommissioned?</p>

<blockquote><p>Release early, release often.</p></blockquote>

<p>~Thoughts in a coffee shop. Saturday the 11th of May 2013.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debbie Millman at Creative Mornings NYC]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/03/debbie-millman-at-creative-mornings-nyc/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-03-03T21:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/03/debbie-millman-at-creative-mornings-nyc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quote from end of a really great presentation titled “<a href="http://vimeo.com/22746156">The Top 10 Things I Wish I Knew When I Graduated College</a>” by Debbie Millman at the February Creative Mornings in New York.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you think that you&#8217;re too busy to do something. I wanna talk to you about what busy means. I think busy is a four letter word. I think busy is never about busy in the sane way that sex is not about sex and money is never about money.</p><p>Busy is a way of organising your priorities and we use being busy or thinking that we’re busy as a reason not to do something that we *really want to do*. If you’re not doing something that you really want to do then you really don’t want to do it. If you really want to do something, you will find the time to do it. Be honest with yourself. If you’re not doing something that you tell yourself that you want to be doing it means that you don’t want to be doing it. Figure out either how to do it or what to do instead.</p><p>Ultimately I think it’s important to consider the two ways of living. You can live out of fear where everything in front of you is something that is unnerving or you can live out of power where everything could be an opportunity if you let it. So I think, in order to strive for a remarkable life, you have to decide that you want one. Because if you expect less, less is all you’re going to get.</p><p>I hope that the force be with you and I thank you for your time and for coming out in this miserable weather.</p><p>Thank you very, very, very, very much.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quote from Mirko Ilic on Design Matters (podcast)]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/quote-from-mirko-ilic-on-design-matters-podcast/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-02-18T19:24:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/quote-from-mirko-ilic-on-design-matters-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few quotes from an interview of Mirko Ilic by Debbie Millman on the Design Matters podcast. You will have to listen to the podcast to hear his great accent (link to podcast in title).</p>

<p>When asked why he didn’t want to work at the New York Times Op-Ed pages for the rest of his life</p>
<blockquote><p>If you stay too long on one place, become routine, and then you can forget, even those beautiful brilliant moments on the beginning, becomes job&#8230;</p></blockquote>

<blockquote><p>I stopped doing comics because I got bored with my own comics&#8230;<br />&#8230; you must entertain yourself in the first place</p></blockquote>

<p>“So Mirko, you love to experiment?”</p>
<blockquote><p>Exactly. And really, business wise, its extremely bad because once, when you start doing something well you just need to cash in. And just do it many of those. But is boring. And I didn&#8217;t become artist to be bored by myself. If is boring to me how boring must be to people who consume that?!</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips from a design technologist]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/tips-from-a-developer-slash-designer/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-02-09T14:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/tips-from-a-developer-slash-designer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was reading an article about becoming a designer and some of the points resonated with me. (via <a href="http://hackdesign.org">hack design</a>)</p>

<blockquote><p>Tip #3: Design everything you do</p><p>&#8230;Your emails should be written/composed clearly and beautifully. Your conversations with individuals should be designed through how you listen, how you maintain eye contact, how you respond (both spoken and unspoken). Everything you do should have a reason, no matter how small. Design requires constant practice, this is a great way to keep growing.</p></blockquote>

<p>I don’t think its possible to design <em>everything</em> but if we keep design in the back of our minds at all times we are more likely to be able to spot problems and design great solutions for them.</p>

<blockquote><p>Tip #7: Focus on defining and solving problems</p><p>A lot of the work you see at design showcase websites are great examples of well executed decorations that lack substance. The people that can perform this type of work are countless and the skills highly commoditized. Avoid pixel-pushing at all costs – your job is to solve problems. View your work through that lens at all times. Always know what problems you are trying to solve while in the process of designing (e.g., people are having a hard time knowing where to go next in a flow, or, the current visual design does not reflect the mood of our brand). Good designers solve problems, great ones ensure they are solving the right ones. Accurately defining the problem goes a long way towards solving it.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is a no brainer but its something which I don’t often think about.</p>

<p>I often see stunning designs and don’t stop to consider what solution they are actually solving (if any) before wishing my designs were as polished. This then leads me down the road of never releasing anything because it isn’t as nice as said design.</p>

<p>The reason this tip resonated with me was that I constantly need to remind myself the importance of of solving a problem rather than creating something beautiful which may not actually achieve what I want. Writing this down it seems so damned obvious but its something I often forget.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/update/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-02-05T21:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while since I last posted however its my aim to post more often than I have in the past.</p>

<p>I will be posting short pieces with my thoughts on content which captures my intrest, of course I will always include links back to the original sources.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[octopress]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2012/04/octopress/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-04-09T14:37:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2012/04/octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m trying out <a href="http://octopress.org">octopress</a>. </p>

<p>As you may or may not have noticed depending on how long after this post was written you are reading this, I have decided to use <a href="http://octopress.org">octopress</a>. If it happens that you are reading this as the second most recent post it is likely that my most recent post is about a different blogging framework which I have decided to use! ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogs I follow]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2012/03/blogs-i-follow/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-03-08T22:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2012/03/blogs-i-follow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are a few of my favorite blogs which I follow.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://daringfireball.net/">daring fireball</a> is a apple centric blog although John Gruber also writes about other businesses occasionally though usually in comparison with apple. This is a great blog for apple news.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.swiss-miss.com/">swiss miss</a> is a swiss designers blog. Tina Roth Eisenberg lives in NYC and reblogs cool and interesting designs. One thing I especially like about this blog is that it is centered around images with a few words accompanying each image.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.farnamstreetblog.com/">farnam street</a> is a blog which have recently started following but it deserves a mention as most things I have read from it have been interesting and thought provoking.</li>
  <li>I used to enjoy following <a href="http://lifehacker.com/">lifehacker</a> but these days I find its just too busy and much of what they post is not interesting to me so I have set up a huge list of filters using yahoo pipes which narrows down the amount I get from here. I’ve been thinking of giving up reading lifehacker though as I rarely find anything interesting on it any more. (if you are interested I have posted a screenshot and link to my filter at the bottom of this post.)</li>
</ul>

<p>Lastly one other thing you should check out for some inspiration, although its not exactly a blog; by which of course I mean its not a blog, is <a href="http://www.creativemornings.com/">creative mornings</a>. Creative mornings is a series of morning talks aimed at creative types which happen all over the world. I have found the New York ones to be especially good.</p>

<p>I think everyone should follow some blogs on topics they are interested as I find they can provide: Information, News, Thought provoking material, New ideas, Inspiration, etcetera, etcetera, etcetera.</p>

<p>If you don’t know about <a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=rss">rss</a> then you should find out about it. I’m sure many people have written very good explanations on what it is and how to use it so I won’t bore you with the details.</p>

<p>The only thing I will say is investigate <a href="http://reader.google.com">google reader</a>. I use google reader to keep my list of rss feeds and manage what I have read but I don’t usually read my feeds directly though it. There are many applications written which sync with google reader and provide a nicer reading experience. The app which I use (and personally love) is <a href="http://reederapp.com/">Reeder</a> which is available for Mac OSX and iOS on the mac/ios app stores respectively.</p>

<p>For those of you who have no idea what an rss reader is, the following is an easy way to think about it. An rss reader is much like an email client only for blog posts rather than emails. You chose to follow the blog posts of a particular site and then any new blog posts by the site are sent to your rss reader as new unread items which you can then read at your leisure. The difference with a mail client and an rss reader is that read items in your rss reader are not kept.</p>

<p>Thats all for now.</p>

<p>Ciao!</p>

<hr />

<p>ps: link and screenshot below as promised
<a href="http://pipes.yahoo.com/pipes/pipe.run?_id=6f6cee9611c7f1481d7e2d3434a3b8b8&amp;_render=rss">my filtered lifehacker rss feed</a> (be warned this will change over time as I add or remove filters)</p>

<p>My filters, as you can see, I filter a large number of terms
<a href="http://intiocean.com/images/content/20120308-lh-filter.png"><img src="http://intiocean.com/images/content/20120308-lh-filter.png" alt="my lifehacker filters" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quote from Steve Jobs 1997]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2012/03/quote-from-steve-jobs-1997/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-03-04T20:52:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2012/03/quote-from-steve-jobs-1997</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The line of code that a developer can write the fastest, the line of code that a developer can maintain the cheapest and the line of code that never breaks for the user is the line of code that the developer never had to write</p><footer><strong>Steve Jobs, Macworld expo in San Fansisco January 7 1997</strong> <cite><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QhhFQ-3w5tE">Video</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Considering the next larger context #quote]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2012/02/considering-the-next-larger-context-quote/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-02-11T09:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2012/02/considering-the-next-larger-context-quote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Always design a thing by considering it in its next larger context - a chair in a room, a room in a house, a house in an environment, an environment in a city plan.</p><footer><strong>Eliel Saarinen</strong> <cite>Growing Object-Oriented Software</cite></footer></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;m reading Growing Object-Oriented Software, Guided By Tests and found this quote in it. I would recommend this book to any developer, I&rsquo;m learning much from it and I&rsquo;ve only read five chapters so far!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Miso and Broccoli soup]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/11/quick-miso-and-broccoli-soup/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-11-28T16:47:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/11/quick-miso-and-broccoli-soup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://intiocean.com/images/content/20111128-miso.jpg" alt="Miso Soup" />
##Ingredients (for 3):
- A little vegetable oil (I use sunflower)
- A teaspoon of sesame oil
- 2 Celery sticks
- 1 Carrot
- 1 Head of broccoli
- Miso paste
- Ginger
- Sesame seeds
- A dash of tabasco or tiny bit of chili in some other form</p>

<h2 id="recipe">Recipe:</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Slice the celery thinly so you get moon shaped slices.</li>
  <li>Peel and slice the carrot into half centimetre circles.</li>
  <li>Put some vegetable oil and the sesame oil in a large saucepan.</li>
  <li>Once the oil is hot, drop in the celery and carrot and saute for 5 minutes.</li>
  <li>Separate the broccoli into florets and add to the pan.</li>
  <li>let it all saute for a few more minutes while stirring regularly to ensure all the brocoli gets mixed in.</li>
  <li>slice some ginger as thin as you can and add to the pan. I would say 5 or so thin slices should do it.</li>
  <li>Boil some water separately in an electric kettle and then add it to the pan. About half a liter of water, enough to generously cover the rest of the vegetables.</li>
  <li> Add Miso paste to taste. 2-3 tablespoons should do the trick.</li>
  <li>Turn the soup off and toast some sesame seeds to sprinkle on top.</li>
  <li>Enjoy!</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding my picture to the header]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/11/adding-my-picture-to-the-header/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-11-19T17:07:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/11/adding-my-picture-to-the-header</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just added my picture to the header of the site. I really like how it turned out. Here are before and after shots:</p>

<p><img src="http://intiocean.com/images/content/20111119-before.jpg" alt="before" /></p>

<p><img src="http://intiocean.com/images/content/20111119-after.jpg" alt="after" /></p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://ruthhardy.co.uk">Ruth</a> for taking the picture. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the design of this site]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/09/on-the-design-of-this-site/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-09-11T20:51:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/09/on-the-design-of-this-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been contemplating redesigning my website. Recently however wordpress updated and now there is a new default theme which comes with it (twenty eleven). I rather like this new theme and can’t convince myself (yet) if I still should redesign…</p>

<p>Does anyone have any thoughts on the matter?</p>

<p>I would like to redesign it so that it doesn’t look like the stock wordpress theme but should I?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inti's butter beans with rice]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/05/intis-butter-beans-with-rice/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-05-30T21:37:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/05/intis-butter-beans-with-rice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="ingredients-for-2">Ingredients: (for 2)</h2>
<p>###For the rice:<br />
- A little oil (personally I like sunflower oil for this)<br />
- 1 large Clove of Garlic (Crushed)<br />
- 1 cup of Basmati Rice (You may not need this much - I do love rice)<br />
- 1.5 cups of Water<br />
- salt to taste (~1/3 tsb)  </p>

<h3 id="for-the-beans">For the Beans:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>A little oil  </li>
  <li>1 medium onion (chopped)  </li>
  <li>1/2 tsb Cumin Seeds  </li>
  <li>~15 Cherry Tomatoes  </li>
  <li>1 tin of Butter Beans  </li>
  <li>1 tbsp Vegetable Stock  </li>
  <li>1/2 cup of Water  </li>
  <li>salt to taste  </li>
  <li>Yogurt (Personally I like greek yogurt but any plain yogurt will do)  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="recipe">Recipe:</h2>
<p>### For the rice:
  * Boil some water
  * Heat the oil and add the crushed garlic and stir
  * Once the garlic is golden (this will be very quick) add the water and the salt
  * Add the rice and cover
  * Once it starts boiling turn down the heat as low as possible and leave to cook for ~20 minutes. After 20 minutes taste the rice to see if it is cooked. If the water dries up before the rice is cooked then add a small amount more. Note: you want the water to dry up completely at the same time as the rice becomes cooked!</p>

<h3 id="for-the-beans-1">For the Beans:</h3>
<p>Once the rice is on start the beans.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Heat the oil and add the chopped onion</li>
  <li>Let the onion simmer stirring occasionally until golden</li>
  <li>Add the cumin seeds and stir for 30 seconds or so</li>
  <li>Add the cherry tomatoes (whole!)</li>
  <li>Drain and rinse the tin of butter beans and then add to the pot.</li>
  <li>Add a little water (~1/2 a cup)</li>
  <li>Add the vegetable stock and salt</li>
  <li>Leave to cook on a medium heat stirring occasionally until the cherry tomatoes have exploded and made the beans tasty.</li>
</ul>

<p>Hopefully by now the rice is just about done and you can eat it :)
Serve with the yogurt which although you might not think would go that well with the tomatoey beans it works a treat.
Enjoy!<br />
Note: The measurements might be a tad off as I usually measure to eye.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Learning Basics of Graphic Design]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/03/learning-basics-of-graphic-design/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-03-12T19:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/03/learning-basics-of-graphic-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve wanted to learn the basics of graphic design for a long time. I even bought <a href="http://www.thamesandhudson.com/9780500285268.html">The Graphic Design School</a> as I thought it would help me get on my way.</p>

<p>After letting it sit on the shelf for a long time and gather dust I have finally taken it down and plan to use it alongside the vast amount of resources available around the web. (I will link to some which I have found useful/interesting below.)</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Lifehacker - <a href="http://lifehacker.com/#!5739492/learn-the-basics-of-design-this-weekend">Learn the basics of Design</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.fontshop.com/education/">Meet Your Type</a> I found this to be a good introduction to typography. It gives an overview of its main aspects, although there is not much detail in the descriptions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.creativemornings.com">Creative mornings</a> - A series of half hour talks given by designers about anything. I’ve been really enjoying these - I’m finding them inspirational and generally thought provoking.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I think the process of learning more about design in general is going to be a slow one but I’m glad I’ve made a start. I hope (and think) that it will prove to be a valuable skill to have as it can influence most of the choices I make thought my life. I will post more thoughts on design when they occur to me but for now I leave you with the following question which is a rephrasing of something I heard. <em>Do you think it is possible to design/make/produce anything that everybody really loves or is it a case of if no one hates it no one is likely to love it either?</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post one]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/02/post-one/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-02-16T20:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/02/post-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know you are all thinking “this is the second post, not the first” but I have decided to call it post one for a number of reasons.</p>

<p>Firstly. The geeky reason: we all know (or do we) that indices start at zero therefore this post has the index one.</p>

<p>Secondly. The non-geeky reason: The first post was automatically generated and not actually created by me so this is in actual fact my first post.</p>

<p>Personally, I prefer the geeky reason.</p>

<p>Before I ramble on too much I would like to talk a little about how I intend to use this site.</p>

<p>I plan to use this site to post thoughts, rambles and perhaps the occasional recipe. I don’t expect to post very often, in fact I expect my posts will be few and far between. The posts on here will be as much for my own reference as anyone else’s, however if you stumble across one of my posts then I hope you have enjoyed reading.</p>

<p>Thats all for now,</p>

<p>Inti</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello world!]]></title>
    
      <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/02/hello-world/"/>
    
    <updated>2011-02-16T18:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/02/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start blogging!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
