<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | Thoughts and other words]]></title>
  <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://intiocean.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-11T14:43:49+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://intiocean.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Inti Ocean]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debbie Millman at Creative Mornings NYC]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/03/debbie-millman-at-creative-mornings-nyc/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-03T21:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/03/debbie-millman-at-creative-mornings-nyc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quote from end of a really great presentation titled “<a href="http://vimeo.com/22746156">The Top 10 Things I Wish I Knew When I Graduated College</a>” by Debbie Millman at the February Creative Mornings in New York.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>If you think that you’re too busy to do something. I wanna talk to you about what busy means. I think busy is a four letter word. I think busy is never about busy in the sane way that sex is not about sex and money is never about money.</p></p><p><p>Busy is a way of organising your priorities and we use being busy or thinking that we’re busy as a reason not to do something that we <em>really want to do</em>. If you’re not doing something that you really want to do then you really don’t want to do it. If you really want to do something, you will find the time to do it. Be honest with yourself. If you’re not doing something that you tell yourself that you want to be doing it means that you don’t want to be doing it. Figure out either how to do it or what to do instead.</p></p><p><p>Ultimately I think it’s important to consider the two ways of living. You can live out of fear where everything in front of you is something that is unnerving or you can live out of power where everything could be an opportunity if you let it. So I think, in order to strive for a remarkable life, you have to decide that you want one. Because if you expect less, less is all you’re going to get.</p></p><p><p>I hope that the force be with you and I thank you for your time and for coming out in this miserable weather.</p></p><p><p>Thank you very, very, very, very much.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quote from Mirko Ilic on Design Matters (podcast)]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/quote-from-mirko-ilic-on-design-matters-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T19:24:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/quote-from-mirko-ilic-on-design-matters-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few quotes from an interview of Mirko Ilic by Debbie Millman on the Design Matters podcast. You will have to listen to the podcast to hear his great accent (link to podcast in title).</p>

<p>When asked why he didn’t want to work at the New York Times Op-Ed pages for the rest of his life
<blockquote><p>If you stay too long on one place, become routine, and then you can forget, even those beautiful brilliant moments on the beginning, becomes job…</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>I stopped doing comics because I got bored with my own comics…<br/>… you must entertain yourself in the first place</p></blockquote></p>

<p>“So Mirko, you love to experiment?”
<blockquote><p>Exactly. And really, business wise, its extremely bad because once, when you start doing something well you just need to cash in. And just do it many of those. But is boring. And I didn’t become artist to be bored by myself. If is boring to me how boring must be to people who consume that?!</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips from a design technologist]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/tips-from-a-developer-slash-designer/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-09T14:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2013/02/tips-from-a-developer-slash-designer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was reading an article about becoming a designer and some of the points resonated with me. (via <a href="http://hackdesign.org">hack design</a>)</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Tip #3: Design everything you do</p></p><p><p>…Your emails should be written/composed clearly and beautifully. Your conversations with individuals should be designed through how you listen, how you maintain eye contact, how you respond (both spoken and unspoken). Everything you do should have a reason, no matter how small. Design requires constant practice, this is a great way to keep growing.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I don’t think its possible to design <em>everything</em> but if we keep design in the back of our minds at all times we are more likely to be able to spot problems and design great solutions for them.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Tip #7: Focus on defining and solving problems</p></p><p><p>A lot of the work you see at design showcase websites are great examples of well executed decorations that lack substance. The people that can perform this type of work are countless and the skills highly commoditized. Avoid pixel-pushing at all costs – your job is to solve problems. View your work through that lens at all times. Always know what problems you are trying to solve while in the process of designing (e.g., people are having a hard time knowing where to go next in a flow, or, the current visual design does not reflect the mood of our brand). Good designers solve problems, great ones ensure they are solving the right ones. Accurately defining the problem goes a long way towards solving it.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This is a no brainer but its something which I don’t often think about.</p>

<p>I often see stunning designs and don’t stop to consider what solution they are actually solving (if any) before wishing my designs were as polished. This then leads me down the road of never releasing anything because it isn’t as nice as said design.</p>

<p>The reason this tip resonated with me was that I constantly need to remind myself the importance of of solving a problem rather than creating something beautiful which may not actually achieve what I want. Writing this down it seems so damned obvious but its something I often forget.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Learning Basics of Graphic Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/03/learning-basics-of-graphic-design/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-12T19:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/03/learning-basics-of-graphic-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve wanted to learn the basics of graphic design for a long time. I even bought <a href="http://www.thamesandhudson.com/9780500285268.html">The Graphic Design School</a> as I thought it would help me get on my way.</p>

<p>After letting it sit on the shelf for a long time and gather dust I have finally taken it down and plan to use it alongside the vast amount of resources available around the web. (I will link to some which I have found useful/interesting below.)</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Lifehacker - <a href="http://lifehacker.com/#!5739492/learn-the-basics-of-design-this-weekend">Learn the basics of Design</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.fontshop.com/education/">Meet Your Type</a> I found this to be a good introduction to typography. It gives an overview of its main aspects, although there is not much detail in the descriptions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.creativemornings.com">Creative mornings</a> - A series of half hour talks given by designers about anything. I’ve been really enjoying these - I’m finding them inspirational and generally thought provoking.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I think the process of learning more about design in general is going to be a slow one but I’m glad I’ve made a start. I hope (and think) that it will prove to be a valuable skill to have as it can influence most of the choices I make thought my life. I will post more thoughts on design when they occur to me but for now I leave you with the following question which is a rephrasing of something I heard. <em>Do you think it is possible to design/make/produce anything that everybody really loves or is it a case of if no one hates it no one is likely to love it either?</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
