<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | Writings by Inti Ocean]]></title>
  <link href="http://intiocean.github.com/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://intiocean.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-04T21:51:41+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://intiocean.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Inti Ocean]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding my picture to the header]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.github.com/blog/2011/11/19/adding-my-picture-to-the-header/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-19T17:07:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.github.com/blog/2011/11/19/adding-my-picture-to-the-header</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just added my picture to the header of the site. I really like how it turned out. Here are before and after shots:</p>

<p><img src="/images/content/20111119-before.jpg" alt="before" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/content/20111119-after.jpg" alt="after" /></p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://ruthhardy.co.uk">Ruth</a> for taking the picture. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the design of this site]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.github.com/blog/2011/09/11/on-the-design-of-this-site/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-11T20:51:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.github.com/blog/2011/09/11/on-the-design-of-this-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been contemplating redesigning my website. Recently however wordpress updated and now there is a new default theme which comes with it (twenty eleven). I rather like this new theme and can't convince myself (yet) if I still should redesign...</p>

<p>Does anyone have any thoughts on the matter?</p>

<p>I would like to redesign it so that it doesn't look like the stock wordpress theme but should I?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Learning Basics of Graphic Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.github.com/blog/2011/03/12/learning-basics-of-graphic-design/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-12T19:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.github.com/blog/2011/03/12/learning-basics-of-graphic-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've wanted to learn the basics of graphic design for a long time. I even bought <a href="http://www.thamesandhudson.com/9780500285268.html">The Graphic Design School</a> as I thought it would help me get on my way.</p>

<p>After letting it sit on the shelf for a long time and gather dust I have finally taken it down and plan to use it alongside the vast amount of resources available around the web. (I will link to some which I have found useful/interesting below.)</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Lifehacker - <a href="http://lifehacker.com/#!5739492/learn-the-basics-of-design-this-weekend">Learn the basics of Design</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.fontshop.com/education/">Meet Your Type</a> I found this to be a good introduction to typography. It gives an overview of its main aspects, although there is not much detail in the descriptions.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.creativemornings.com">Creative mornings</a> - A series of half hour talks given by designers about anything. I've been really enjoying these - I'm finding them inspirational and generally thought provoking.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>I think the process of learning more about design in general is going to be a slow one but I'm glad I've made a start. I hope (and think) that it will prove to be a valuable skill to have as it can influence most of the choices I make thought my life. I will post more thoughts on design when they occur to me but for now I leave you with the following question which is a rephrasing of something I heard. <em>Do you think it is possible to design/make/produce anything that everybody really loves or is it a case of if no one hates it no one is likely to love it either?</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
