<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: recipes | Thoughts and other words]]></title>
  <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/categories/recipes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://intiocean.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-11T19:09:48+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://intiocean.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Inti Ocean]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Miso and Broccoli soup]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/11/quick-miso-and-broccoli-soup/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-28T16:47:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/11/quick-miso-and-broccoli-soup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/content/20111128-miso.jpg" alt="Miso Soup" />
##Ingredients (for 3):
- A little vegetable oil (I use sunflower)
- A teaspoon of sesame oil
- 2 Celery sticks
- 1 Carrot
- 1 Head of broccoli
- Miso paste
- Ginger
- Sesame seeds
- A dash of tabasco or tiny bit of chili in some other form</p>

<h2 id="recipe">Recipe:</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Slice the celery thinly so you get moon shaped slices.</li>
  <li>Peel and slice the carrot into half centimetre circles.</li>
  <li>Put some vegetable oil and the sesame oil in a large saucepan.</li>
  <li>Once the oil is hot, drop in the celery and carrot and saute for 5 minutes.</li>
  <li>Separate the broccoli into florets and add to the pan.</li>
  <li>let it all saute for a few more minutes while stirring regularly to ensure all the brocoli gets mixed in.</li>
  <li>slice some ginger as thin as you can and add to the pan. I would say 5 or so thin slices should do it.</li>
  <li>Boil some water separately in an electric kettle and then add it to the pan. About half a liter of water, enough to generously cover the rest of the vegetables.</li>
  <li> Add Miso paste to taste. 2-3 tablespoons should do the trick.</li>
  <li>Turn the soup off and toast some sesame seeds to sprinkle on top.</li>
  <li>Enjoy!</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inti's butter beans with rice]]></title>
    <link href="http://intiocean.com/words/2011/05/intis-butter-beans-with-rice/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-30T21:37:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://intiocean.com/words/2011/05/intis-butter-beans-with-rice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="ingredients-for-2">Ingredients: (for 2)</h2>
<p>###For the rice:<br />
- A little oil (personally I like sunflower oil for this)<br />
- 1 large Clove of Garlic (Crushed)<br />
- 1 cup of Basmati Rice (You may not need this much - I do love rice)<br />
- 1.5 cups of Water<br />
- salt to taste (~1/3 tsb)  </p>

<h3 id="for-the-beans">For the Beans:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>A little oil  </li>
  <li>1 medium onion (chopped)  </li>
  <li>1/2 tsb Cumin Seeds  </li>
  <li>~15 Cherry Tomatoes  </li>
  <li>1 tin of Butter Beans  </li>
  <li>1 tbsp Vegetable Stock  </li>
  <li>1/2 cup of Water  </li>
  <li>salt to taste  </li>
  <li>Yogurt (Personally I like greek yogurt but any plain yogurt will do)  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="recipe">Recipe:</h2>
<p>### For the rice:
  * Boil some water
  * Heat the oil and add the crushed garlic and stir
  * Once the garlic is golden (this will be very quick) add the water and the salt
  * Add the rice and cover
  * Once it starts boiling turn down the heat as low as possible and leave to cook for ~20 minutes. After 20 minutes taste the rice to see if it is cooked. If the water dries up before the rice is cooked then add a small amount more. Note: you want the water to dry up completely at the same time as the rice becomes cooked!</p>

<h3 id="for-the-beans-1">For the Beans:</h3>
<p>Once the rice is on start the beans.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Heat the oil and add the chopped onion</li>
  <li>Let the onion simmer stirring occasionally until golden</li>
  <li>Add the cumin seeds and stir for 30 seconds or so</li>
  <li>Add the cherry tomatoes (whole!)</li>
  <li>Drain and rinse the tin of butter beans and then add to the pot.</li>
  <li>Add a little water (~1/2 a cup)</li>
  <li>Add the vegetable stock and salt</li>
  <li>Leave to cook on a medium heat stirring occasionally until the cherry tomatoes have exploded and made the beans tasty.</li>
</ul>

<p>Hopefully by now the rice is just about done and you can eat it :)
Serve with the yogurt which although you might not think would go that well with the tomatoey beans it works a treat.
Enjoy!<br />
Note: The measurements might be a tad off as I usually measure to eye.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
